<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>hypoxia on VRX Academic Site</title>
    <link>https://vrx-.github.io/tags/hypoxia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in hypoxia on VRX Academic Site</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy {year};</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://vrx-.github.io/tags/hypoxia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Hypoxic extent</title>
      <link>https://vrx-.github.io/research/extent/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vrx-.github.io/research/extent/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Models allow a dynamic estimate of the hypoxic region in the Texas-Louisiana Shelf. While annual summer cruise observations capture a static vision of what is expected to be the largest extent of the season (late July or early August), models simulate the development of the region in time. Although model simulations are not completely accurate, they give an estimation driven by realistic hydrodynamic settings. 20 years of model output capture a wide range of interannual variability.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Patchiness</title>
      <link>https://vrx-.github.io/research/patchiness/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vrx-.github.io/research/patchiness/</guid>
      <description>











  


&lt;video controls &gt;
  &lt;source src=&#34;bo_sum2010.mp4&#34; type=&#34;video/mp4&#34;&gt;
&lt;/video&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To reproduce variability within the hypoxic region, models need to resolve sub-mesoscale (100 m to 10 km) and mesoscale (10 to 100 km) dynamic processes. Hourly simulations of a simple oxygen parametrization incorporated in a high resolution hydrodynamic model, show the formation and destruction of eddy-like features and fronts in the bottom oxygen structure. Due to the difficulty of sampling, these features have not been fully observed but hinted by high-resolution Acrobat measurements (DiMarco and Zimmerle, 2017).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
